

Sahil Suresh

MD-PhD Candidate at Tufts University School of Medicine





+1-508-494-6860



sahilsuresh@gmail.com



Boston, MA

About Me

Detail-oriented researcher with 8 years of research experience, specializing in developing computational models to better understand neural mechanisms underlying neuropsychiatric disorders, with a particular interest in using datadriven approaches to improve diagnostic precision and therapeutic strategies

₩ Skills

- Python
- Full Stack Software Development
- MATLAB
- Blender
- Bonsai
- HTML/CSS
- PyTorch, ML
- PsychoPy Task Design
- Mathematical Modeling

Education

MSTP Candidate

Tufts University School of Medicine

2022-Current

- Dual-degree MD-PhD student Concentration in computational neuroscience
- Trainee under Dr. Michael Halassa, MD, PhD

Bachelor of Arts, cum laude

Cornell University

2015-2019

- Major in Biological Sciences Concentration in Neurobiology and Behavior
- Minors in Psychology and Creative Writing
- Cumulative GPA: 3.74
- President of Cornell's Cardiology Group, Publicity Chair of Cornell's Quill Guild, Peer Mentor for Cornell's Undergraduate Research Board, Graphics Designer for Mario Einaudi Diversity Center's South Asia Program

Experience

Staff Associate

Zuckerman Institute of Neuroscience at Columbia University

2020 - 2022

- Utilizing two-photon microscopy to assess sensory representation in the posterior dorsolateral striatum and how this representation is affected by learning.
- Advised by Dr. Rui Costa, DVM, PhD

Research Associate

NYU Langone Health

2019 - 2022

- Assessing the role of the posterior dorsolateral striatum in directing sensoryguided actions in the context of reward-driven behaviors.
- · Advised by Dr. Tanya Sippy, MD, PhD

Clinical Research Coordinator

Icahn School of Medicine at Mt. Sinai

Aug 2019 - Dec 2019

- Primary coordinator of Alnylam's natural history study of the Porphyrias.
- Secondary coordinator on Phase III trials of Givosiran, a treatment for Acute Intermittent Porphyria.
- Advised by Dr. Manisha Balwani, MD, MS

Research Assistant

Cornell University

2016 - 2019

- Creating a metaethics scale that ascertains an individual's alignment with moral objectivism or moral relativism.
- Determining anatomical and functional characterization of the neural circuits responsible for regulating food ingestion in Drosophila melanogaster.
- Honors Thesis: Phenotypically characterizing Drosophila melanogaster mutants deficient in receptors for Allatostatin-C.
- Advised by Dr. Nilay Yapici, PhD, Dr. David Pizarro, PhD, Dr. Matthew Meiselman, PhD and Dr. Lance Bush, PhD

Select Publications

1. Huang, A.S., Wimmer, R.D., Lam, N.H., Wang, B.A., **Suresh, S.**, Roeske, M.J., Pleger, B., Halassa, M.M., and Woodward, N.D. A prefrontal thalamocortical readout for conflict-related executive dysfunction in schizophrenia. Cell Reports Medicine. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrm.2024.101802.